Sai Jayanth Kumar Dindukurthi

Mobile: 9742729479

Email: dsaijayanthkumar2@gmail.com

**PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:** 

➤ Having 7 years of Experience on Web Developing Applications using Angular 2/4/6/8/10/12, HTML5,

CSS3,TypeScript,

JavaScript, jQuery and RWD (Bootstrap) Technologies.

➤ Having professional experience in Web-Development Front End Applications.

> Having Working Experience on implementing Design Patterns and modern front-end template frameworks for

Typescript including Bootstrap, jQuery, HTML, CSS & Angular.

Handled in RESTful Web Services/API's.

Experienced in working with agile methodology.

Handled all the client side validations, hide and show controls using Angular.

Ability to grasp and apply new concepts quickly and effectively.

Experience in using version controls such as SVN, Git, Sourcetree.

> Experience in using tools like **Postman.** 

Ability to Work in any environments.

**WORK EXPERIENCE:** 

> Previously worked in **IBM India Pvt Ltd** from April 2016 to Sep 2019.

➤ Previously worked in Capgemini India Pvt ltd from Nov 2019 – April 2021.

Previously worked in Accenture India Pvt ltd from April 2021 – Jan 2023

Currently working in EY India Pvt Ltd from Jan 2023 to till now

**EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS:** 

> B. Tech (Bachelor of Technology - ECE) from JNTU, Anantapur, Andhra Pradesh in 2014.

## **TECHNICAL SUMMARY**

Skills : Angular 12, Angular 10, Angular 8, Angular 6, Angular 4, Angular 2, HTML, CSS,

Javascript, Typescript, Bootstrap, Unit testing, Karma/Jasmine framework,

Angular Material, NgRX store, RX JS

Framework : Angular2/4/6/8/10/12

Web Technologies : HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Bootstrap, JavaScript

Database : SQL Server

Operating System : Windows 7, Windows 10

IDEs : VS Code

Other Tools : Jira, Bitbucket, Postman, GIT, TortoiseGIT

# PROJECT: #1

Company: EY India pvt ltd

Client: Barclays

Project Name: Reclite 2.0

Technologies: HTML5, CSS, TypeScript, Bootstrap, Angular12

**Tools**: Git, Bitbucket

**Duration**: January 2023 – Till now **Designation**: Senior Angular Developer

Description: Reclite 2.0 is a Reconciliation application where we can use in banking sector

Design, build and configure applications to meet business process in Reclite 2.0

Development of general component using angular 12

Writing cosmetics for web application using CSS to make application responsive in all devices.

Integrating services for commonly used shared API

Unit testing of features using Jasmine framework

Defect fixing

# PROJECT: #1

**Company:** Accenture India Pvt Ltd **Client**: UKG (Ultimate Kronos Group)

Project Name: Workflow UI

Technologies: HTML5, CSS, TypeScript, Bootstrap, Angular10

Tools: Git

**Duration**: May 2021 – Till now **Designation**: Angular Developer

Description:

Design, build and configure applications to meet business process in UKG Application

- Development of custom component and general component using angular 10
- Writing cosmetics for web application using CSS
- Integrating services for commonly used shared API
- Unit testing of features using Jasmine framework
- Defect fixing



Company: Capgemini India Pvt ltd

Client: CISCO

Project Name: ACE (Advance Cisco Experience)

Technologies: HTML5, CSS, TypeScript, Bootstrap, Angular10

Tools: Git

**Duration**: July 2020 – April 2021 **Designation**: Angular Developer

Description:

ACE CISCO Development of UI for ACE Application

- Development of custom component and general component using angular 10
- Writing cosmetics for web application using CSS3
- Writing services for commonly used shared API
- Unit testing of features using Jasmine framework
- Defect fixing

## PROJECT: #3

Company: Capgemini India Pvt ltd

Client: JnJ

Project Name: C4T (Care 4 Today)

Technologies: HTML5, CSS, TypeScript, Bootstrap, Angular8

**Tools**: Postman, Swagger, Git **Duration**: Nov 2019 – June 2020 **Designation**: Angular Developer

**Description:** 

This web application is for their Hospitals which helps HCPs and Patients to interact with each other and manage treatment related information. Following are the features we have developed in this portal.

- On Boarding a Patient by generating Unique Onboarding codes based on specific Hospital and Care Module.
- Group chat between different HCPs and Patients.
- Managing appointments between HCPs and Patients.
- Ability to add, edit and delete prefill templates for Appointments and Messages.

## **Roles and Responsibilities:**

- Understanding the requirements through User Stories in Jira and oral communication with the manager.
- Developing responsive UI screens based on specifications provided by UX team with using HTML5, and Bootstrap.
- Implemented Validations for Forms using predefined Validations in Angular8 Framework.
- Developed functionalities in web pages using angular features like Components, Services, Http Requests,
  Templates, Observables, Data Binding and Routing Created components, Services, Directives, Routing, Pipes using
  Angular CLI
- Successfully handled JSON data and carried out JSON parsing for form submissions and DOM manipulation.
- Maintain consistency in design and layout.

# PROJECT: #4

Company: IBM India Pvt Ltd

Client: Uniliver

Project Name: Uniliver

Technologies: HTML5, CSS, TypeScript, Bootstrap, Angular 4,6

**Duration**: June-2018 to Sep- 2019 **Designation**: Angular Developer

**Description:** 

Invoice document was treated as assert and processes in block chain through various stages. Pre validations are done using Block chain Integrator. Finally processed invoices are posted to DCIW systems.

#### **Roles and Responsibilities:**

- Used Router for implementing routing in the application.
- Involved in developing the user interface, for invoking the logic, and displaying pages respectively.
- Have an overview, understanding about different features of Angular like Components, Services, Http, Templates,

**Data Binding and Routing** 

- Created components, Services, Directives, Routing, Pipes using Angular CLI
- Developing angular events and bindings.
- Integrating the API's.
- Fixing the defects, responsive issues in developed user interfaces.
- Successfully handled JSON data and carried out JSON parsing for form submissions and DOM manipulation.

## PROJECT: #5

Client: Arco

Project name: Arco Web Design re-engineering

Technologies: HTML5, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap, JavaScript, LESS

**Duration**: May-2017 to June-2018 **Designation**: Web Developer

Arco is B2B project and it is the UK based leading supplier of safety equipment, workwear, safety boots and shoes, gloves and maintenance supplies. Arco's mission is to keep people safe at work.

The objective of the project is to replace the Arco Broad Vision site with a new generation of site based on SAP Hybris. The aim of the project is to deliver B2B commerce, SAP Hybris, ongoing support and maintenance for the system, UX design and integration with an existing SAP environment. National Distribution Centre holds an impressive 22,000 products and network of over 40 branches cover the UK and Ireland.

### **Roles and Responsibilities:**

- Design and develop layouts, Pages and Modal Popups for the UX screens using HTML5, Bootstrap, LESS and Integration of those in JSP pages.
- Worked on ajax calls for dynamic data display and integrating HTML code with backend code in JSP.
- Worked on the web responsiveness for the store pages
- Creating RWD template and integrating it to .jsp file. Writing JavaScript and JQuery functionality for custom methods.
- Designed front-end web pages using HTML, CSS, JSP and JavaScript, JQuery
- Taking Care for UI related Bugs and implementation
- Consuming REST APIs through AJAX calls.
- Testing the functionalities of the Application in all Browsers like IE, FF and Chrome..
- Experience in SDLC and Agile Methodology

## PROJECT: #6

**Client**: CCE (Common Commerce Engine)

Project name: Stella Commerce

Technologies: HTML5, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript

**Duration**: Feb-2016 to May-2017 **Designation**: Web Developer

CCE is a commerce engine for the worldwide IBM.COM e-Commerce websites which hosts over 4000 B2B/B2C stores for IBM, Lenovo and its associate companies worldwide. I have worked on **IBM Employee Purchase Program, which** is an ecommerce site where we are selling electronic goods to IBM employees, friends, family and contactors in US and Canada. Stella is based on Agile methodology hence familiar with all concepts regarding agile like daily scrum, creating user stories and tasks, refinement calls.

## **Roles and Responsibilities:**

- Worked on the web responsiveness for the store pages
- Designed front-end pages using HTML, CSS, JSP and JavaScript
- Developed website which is simple, professional, user-friendly, user-tracking, very less load time.
- Worked on north star front end changes
- Analyse and fix errors/bugs for the CCE sites reported by clients.
- Experience in SDLC and Agile Methodology.
- Maintain consistency in design and layout.

#### **Declaration:**

	I hereby declare that all the particulars stated above are true to the best of my knowledge and assure	that I will put
the best	of myself.	

Place:	(D Sai Jayanth Kumar)
Date:	